<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on Ritvik Banakar</title>
    <link>https://www.ritvik.dev/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on Ritvik Banakar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Ritvik Banakar. Built with&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#39;https://www.ritvik.dev/about-blog&#39;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 13:47:08 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ritvik.dev/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Matter</title>
      <link>https://www.ritvik.dev/posts/books/b320/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 13:47:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ritvik.dev/posts/books/b320/</guid>
      <description>Book 3 Started &amp;amp; Finished June 3rd 2020
Review 4/5
Thoughts Similar to Recursion, Dark Matter is yet another sci-fi thriller. Although the plot was slightly less convoluting, I felt a stronger connection to each of the characters. This book is a fun read and I recommend it for anyone interested in science fiction and mystery. Revolving on the idea of regret, the book provides a unique take on those moments when we wonder what if&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Win Friends &amp; Influence People</title>
      <link>https://www.ritvik.dev/posts/books/b220/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 13:47:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ritvik.dev/posts/books/b220/</guid>
      <description>Book 2 Finished May 2020
Review 2/5
Thoughts Dale Carnegie&amp;rsquo;s book follows a very simple structure of lesson, example, and finally reiteration of said lesson. I think that at first, the book was intriguing but after I had completed about a third of the book it began getting boring as it felt very repetitive. The numerous examples began having predictable outcomes and the lessons just felt dated as nowadays, many of his &amp;ldquo;rules&amp;rdquo; are just common sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recursion</title>
      <link>https://www.ritvik.dev/posts/books/b120/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ritvik.dev/posts/books/b120/</guid>
      <description>Book 1 Started &amp;amp; Finished May 7th 2020
Review 4.5/5
Thoughts I thought this book was great. It&amp;rsquo;s a relatively short read and for those interested in a sci-fi thriller this is a must read. The story kept me hooked and every time you thought you knew what was going on, a whole new twist appears. For those who haven&amp;rsquo;t read in a while and would like to get back, I highly recommend this book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“If you don’t like to read, you haven’t found the right book.”</title>
      <link>https://www.ritvik.dev/posts/experiment1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 13:47:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ritvik.dev/posts/experiment1/</guid>
      <description>Goal One Read 52 books in 2020
Write a brief summary and takeaway for each book.
Why? Books are an incredible dense source of material in which through active engagement, one can understand decades worth of research. Through my summaries and takeaways I hope to encourage others to read more and learn a few lessons along the way :)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>